Guide to the Kevin Opstedal Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Kevin Opstedal papers
1970-2012
YCAL MSS 1120
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
3.12
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, notebooks, sketchbooks, audiovisual materials, printed materials, and other papers by or relating to poet Kevin Opstedal. It documents his work as a poet, as well as his research interest in the poets of Bolinas, California.
Opstedal, Kevin, 1956-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Granary Books, Inc. on the Ezra Pound Archive Fund and the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2011, 2012.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 5 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Kevin Opstedal
Kevin Opstedal is an American poet.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of correspondence, writings, notebooks, sketchbooks, audiovisual materials, printed materials, and other papers by or relating to poet Kevin Opstedal. It documents his work as a poet, as well as his research interest in the poets of Bolinas, California.
Arrangement
Organized into two groupings: April 2011 Acquisition and May 2012 Acquisition.
American poetry -- 20th Century; American poetry -- 21st century; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Poets, American -- 21st century -- Archives; Audiovisual materials; Sketchbooks; Poets -- United States -- 20th Century; Poets -- United States -- 21st century; Opstedal, Kevin, 1956-
- April 2011 Acquisition, 1971-2008; 1.21; (2 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The April 2011 Acquisition consists of papers relating to poets in Bolinas, California, including corresondence, writings by Kevin Opstedal, writings by others, printed materials, and audiovisual materials.
  - Correspondence and manuscript material
    - Bolinas Inventory (Box 4)
    - Berkson, Bill (Box 4)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Audiovisual materials, "Berkson / Kyger - 5/2/87", Box 2.
    - Clark, Tom (Box 4)
      See also: Audiovisual materials, "Tom Clark - 1-31-87", Box 2.
    - Clarke, John (Box 4)
    - Creeley, Robert (Box 4)
    - Herd, Dale (Box 4)
    - Kyger, Joanne (Box 4)
      See also: Audiovisual materials, "Joanne Kyger - 3/7/87", Box 2.
    - MacAdams, Lewis (Box 4)
      See also: Audiovisual materials, "Lewis MacAdams - 12/23/86", Box 2.
    - McNaughton, Duncan (Box 4)
    - Saroyan, Aram (Box 4)
    - Veitch, Tom (Box 4)
    - Waldman, Anne (Box 4)
    - Warsh, Lewis (Box 4)
    - Weishaus, Joel (Box 4)
    - Whalen, Philip (Box 4)
    - Wolfe, Michael (Box 4)
  - Writings by Kevin Opstedal, 2001-2008
    - All this Every Day: Poetry, Poets and Community in Bolinas, California, 1967-1980 - final copy, 2008 (Box 4)
    - At Bolinas: A Literary History of the San Andreas Fault: Bolinas Section, 1967-1980 - 1st draft (Box 4)
    - At Bolinas: A Literary History of the San Andreas Fault: Bolinas Section, 1967-1980 - 2nd draft, 2007 Jan. 31 (Box 4)
    - A Literary History of the San Andreas Fault: Bolinas Section (Box 4)
    - Drafts - At Bolinas, 2 (Box 4)
    - Dreaming as One: Poetry, Poets and Community in Bolinas, California, 1967-1980 - online version, circa 2001 (Box 4)
  - Writings by others
    - Berkman, Bill - California Letters, 2 (Box 4)
    - Berrigan, Ted and Tom Clark - Bolinas Eyewash (Box 4)
    - MacAdams, Lewis and Tom Clark - Expeditions (Box 4)
  - Other papers, 1971-1977
    - The Bolinas HIT - nos. 1-2 (Box 4)
    - The Paper, 1971; 2 (Box 4)
    - Review of "On the Mesa" (Box 4)
    - Turkey Buzzard Review, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Untitled Magazine - 2 issues, 1973 March-April (Box 4)
  - Audiovisual material, 1986-1987
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - "Berkson / Kyger", 1987 May 2; 1; 01:35:21; The program was recorded at a low level. There is a high amount of hiss and background noise on the tape. The program is barely audible at times. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002099362254)
      Contains a taped interview.
    - "Joanne Kyger", 1987 March 7; 1; 01:25:53; There is high background noise on the tape. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002099362262)
    - "Lewis MacAdams", 1986 December 23; 1; 01:33:38; The program is distorted at times. There is a high amount of buzz and static on the tape. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002099362270)
    - "Tom Clark", 1987 January 1; 1; 00:59:26; The program was recorded at a very low level. There is a high amount of hiss and static on the tape. There is background noise on the tape. The program is barely audible at times. (Box 5, Item barcode 39002099362288)
- May 2012 Acquisition, 1970s-2012; 1.92; (3 boxes)
  The May 2012 Acquisition consists of correspondence, writings, notebooks, artwork, and other papers by or relating to Kevin Opstedal.
  - Correspondence, 1976-2012
    - Kim Abeles, 2002 (Box 1)
    - Micah Ballard, 2000-2012 (Box 1)
    - Samuel Beckett, 1976 (Box 1)
    - Bill Berkson, 1996-2002 (Box 1)
    - Noel Black, circa 2000 (Box 1)
    - Tom Clark, 1985-1999 (Box 1)
    - Albert Flynn Desilver, 1998-2002 (Box 1)
    - Edward Dorn, 1990s (Box 1)
    - Jennifer Dorn, 1999 (Box 1)
    - Patrick Dunagan, 2000s (Box 1)
    - Elaine Equi, circa 2000 (Box 1)
    - Anselm Hollo, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Tim Kindseth, 2003 (Box 1)
    - Joanne Kyger and Donald Guravich, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
    - Lewis MacAdams, 2000s (Box 1)
    - Duncan McNaughton, 2000s (Box 1)
    - F. A. Nettelbeck, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
    - Erik Noonan, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
    - Alice Notley, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Ron Padgett, 2001-2006 (Box 1)
    - Simon Pettet, 1990s (Box 1)
    - Michael Price, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
    - Mark Salerno, 2001-2004 (Box 1)
    - Cedar Sigo, 2001-2009 (Box 1)
    - Dale Smith, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
    - Mark Terrill, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
    - Sunnylyn Thibodeaux, 2000s (Box 1)
    - Philip Whalen, 1988 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, circa 2000 (Box 1)
  - Writings and related papers, 1970s-2000s
    - Writings, 1970s-2000s (Box 1)
      Contains various writings and poems, including material used in Kevin Opstedal's 2007 book: User's Manual to the Pacific Coast Highway.
    - Flyers / Posters (Box 1)
    - Books, 1990s-2000s (Box 1)
      Contains material relating to books by Kevin Opstedal, including a print-out of the cover of Like Rain, a poetry project newsletter from April / May 1998, print-out from litpress.com regarding Sand in the Vaseline, a print of the cover for Coastal Disturbance, and a proof of Variable High Cloudiness.
  - Notebooks, 1982-1996
    - 1982 (Box 1)
    - 1987-1988 (Box 1)
    - 1988, 3 (Box 1)
    - circa 1989, 3 (Box 1)
    - circa 1990, 4 (Box 1)
    - circa 1992, 2 (Box 2)
    - 1993-1995 (Box 2)
    - circa 1995 (Box 2)
    - 1996 (Box 2)
  - Artwork
    - Printing blocks, circa 1985 (Box 2)
      Contains three printing blocks relating to Kamikaze Blvd. (1985).
    - Artwork (Box 3 (Oversize))
      Contains art material related to Sunset Revisited, Like Rain and El Tsunami, as well as other books and projects. Also contained within is a portrait of Samuel Beckett by Kevin Opstedal.
    - Sketchbooks (Box 3 (Oversize))
      Contains three sketchbooks.